onto-med.de 2019-05-12

# Privacy Policy

**This privacy policy applies to the website accessible via onto-med.de or ontomed.de of the Institute for Medical Informatics, Statistics and Epidemiology (IMISE) of the University of Leipzig.**

## access data

When visiting our web pages, our web servers temporarily stores any access in log files (so-called server log files). Access data includes:

  * The IP address of the device used by you for page retrieval (PC, smartphone, tablet, ...)
  * The date and time of access
  * Name and URL of the retrieved website
  * Message about successful retrieval or error (for example, file not found)
  * The transferred amount of data
  * Recognition data of your web page viewer (hereinafter referred to as "browser or" web browser ") and operating system of the requesting device (if provided by the requesting web browser)
  * The address of the previously visited website (Referrer URL), if you have reached there from a reference to our offer (if transmitted by the requesting web browser)

The collection and processing of this data is for the purpose of operation, system security and optimization of the Internet offer. A storage of this data together with other personal data of the user does not take place. The IMISE reserves the right to evaluate the log data retrospectively, if there are concrete indications for the reasonable suspicion of illegal use. 

The data stored in the log files will be deleted after no later than seven days. Further storage is possible. In this case, the IP addresses are deleted or alienated, so that assignment of the calling client is no longer possible.

## Handling of personal data

Personal data is information about a specific or identifiable person. The personal data include, for example, the name, telephone number or e-mail address.

We only collect personal data for processing and use, if you voluntarily decide to enter the data or expressly give your consent. Any use of your personal data takes place only in order to complete your request directed to us. A transfer of your data to third parties will not take place without your explicit consent, unless we are forced for legal reasons to a disclosure.

Personal data will be deleted as soon as the purpose of the storage is omitted.

## safety

The IMISE uses technical and organizational security measures to protect your personal data managed by us against accidental or intentional manipulation, loss, destruction or access by unauthorized persons. Our security measures are continuously improved in line with technological developments.

We point out that data transmission by e-mail is usually unsecured. It can't be ruled out that transmitted data can be read by unauthorized persons and possibly even falsified.

## cookies

Our website uses cookies to store technical session control data in your browser's memory or your device's data memory. This data will be deleted when you close your browser.

Furthermore, we use cookies to permanently hide the cookie banner when you click 'Accept'.

Of course, our websites can also be viewed without cookies. About the settings of most browsers you can disable the storage of cookies. However, it is possible that parts of our Internet offer no longer or only partially work if you do not accept cookies.

## Right to information, revocation, changes, corrections and updates

You have the right to information concerning the personal data stored about you. In addition, you have the right to correct, block and delete this personal information.

## Data Protection Officer

Matthias Collier

Postal address: 

Matthias Collier  
Universitaet Leipzig  
Institut fuer Medizinische Informatik, Statistik und Epidemiologie  
Haertelstrasse 16-18  
04107 LEIPZIG  
GERMANY

Phone: +49 341 97 16186
